In Palestine, Israel has thus far been highly successful in forcibly establishing itself
both as a colonial reality and as a powerful nation-state in a post-colonial age.
It has done this while always assuming a false posture of self-defense,
which I'm sure will be familiar to most of you.
The great historian and theoretician of colonialism, Patrick Wolfe,
who sadly just passed away, wrote the following.
I'm quoting Patrick Wolfe.
Settler colonies were, in brackets, are, premised on the elimination of the native societies.
The split tensing were, are, the split tensing reflects a determinate feature of settler colonization.
The colonizers come to stay.
Invasion is a structure, not an event.
He's thinking, of course, of Australia.
You could say the same thing about New Zealand.
You could say the same thing about Canada or the United States.
But think of those words in regard to Palestine.
In Palestine, both that structure and the war that resulted from it are still ongoing today, after 100 years.
It is a war that seems endless to the Palestinians themselves.